Guide to the GAPIMNY Records TAM.675
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
GAPIMNY Records
1994-2020, ongoing
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
GAPIMNY
Chin, Dennis
Tseng, Jason
TAM.675
7 Linear Feet in 3 record cartons, 2 manuscript boxes, 3 oversize flat boxes, and 1 small artifact box
3 websites in 3 archived websites.
GAPIMNY, formerly known as the Gay and Pacific Islander Men of New York, is a volunteer-run community organization that provides social, educational, and cultural programming for gay, lesbian, bisexual, two-spirit, transgender, same-gender loving, gender non-conforming, queer, and questioning people who are Asian Pacific Islander in the greater New York City area. In collaboration with other community organizations, GAPIMNY works to provide peer-support, educational resources, and programming on issues such as race, sexuality, gender, public health, and immigration law. Materials include pamphlets, flyers, leaflets, brochures, stickers, photographs, newsletters, correspondence, meeting memoranda, websites, and some artifacts that were used in parades or demonstrations. The collection also includes magazines, literary journals, and materials produced by related organizations. This collection documents individual activists and community organizations providing support and resources for its membership, and addressing concerns of visibility, representation, and marginalization.
Conditions Governing Access
Materials are open without restrictions.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Donated by Dennis Chin and Jason Tseng on behalf of the Gay Asian and Pacific Islander Men of New York (GAPIMNY) in 2015. The accession numbers associated with this gift are 2015.046 and 2015.052. In August 2021, Binh Hoang donated an accretion of administrative records; the accession number for this gift is 2021.037.
In December 2019, https://gaysiandiaries.com/ and http://gapimny.org/ were added to the web archive captured through the use of Archive-it. Archive-It uses web crawling technology to capture websites at a scheduled time and displays only an archived copy, from the resulting WARC file, of the website. The accession number associated with this website is 2020.013. In 2025, https://linktr.ee/gapimny/ was added. The accession number assocaited with this website is 2026.019.
Appraisal
Two 3.5 inch floppy disks were discarded after imagining process determined there was no data present.
Arrangement
Files are arranged alphabetically by title or subject.
Historical Note
GAPIMNY is a volunteer-run community organization that provides social, educational, and cultural programming for gay, lesbian, bisexual, two-spirit, transgender, same-gender loving, gender non-conforming, queer, and questioning people who are Asians Pacific Islander in the greater New York City area. In collaboration with other community organizations, GAPIMNY works to provide peer-support, educational resources, and programming on issues such as race, sexuality, gender, public health, and immigration law. GAPIMNY was founded as the Gay and Pacific Islander Men of New York in 1990 by Don Kao, John Chin, and John Manzon. In the early 1990s, GAPIMNY organized with related groups to achieve greater visibility within the LGBTQ+ community and protest stereotypical public representations of Asian men and women. As the organization grew, it started hosting workshops for its community, established an online presence, and organized DynasTea, the organization's featured event from 1997 until 2006. In 2010, the organization debuted a newsmagazine called PersuAsian. GAPIMNY has increasingly partnered with other organizations to lead workshops and sponsor public programs on issues such as visibility, immigration, public health, and marriage equality. Some such collaborations include the Asian American Legal Defense and Education Fund, Asian Pacific American Coalition for Equality (APACE), Asian Media Watchdog, and Asian Queer United in Action (AQUA). Programs and campaigns include participation in Chinatown's Lunar New Year Parade; continued protest over various examples of racial discrimination, homophobia, or transphobia; and DowneTime, a support program to provide a confidential space to discuss identity issues, attend health workshops, and connect with other members of the community. In 2018 the name of the organization changed from Gay and Pacific Islander Men of New York to GAPIMNY.
Source: https://wayback.archive-it.org/13239/20191210193116/http://gapimny.org/gapimny-history/
Related Archival Materials
Asian American Legal Defense and Education Fund Records (TAM.321)
Scope and Contents
This collection consists of material created and collected by GAPIMNY during the mid-1990s through 2026 in the course of their social, educational, and cultural programming for gay, lesbian, bisexual, two-spirit, transgender, same-gender loving, gender non-conforming, queer, and questioning people who are Asian Pacific Islander in the New York City area. Materials created by GAPIMNY include pamphlets, flyers, leaflets, brochures, stickers, photographs, newsletters, correspondence, meeting memoranda, websites, and some artifacts that were used in parades or demonstrations. Many of these materials were used or intended for distribution, with both general informational documents about the organization and materials specific to particular events or individual advocacy campaigns related to issues such as racism, immigration, or public health. The ephemeral formats present display some of the methods by which the organization sought to reach out to and advocate for its membership. Some of the GAPIMNY initiatives documented in the collection include the multilingual "Love Has No Borders" campaign and the "(In)Visibly American" immigration program. The collection also includes magazines, literary journals, and materials produced by related organizations, the most prominent being the National Queer Asian Pacific Islander Alliance (NQAPIA). This collection documents individual activists and community organizations providing support and resources for its membership, and addressing concerns of visibility, representation, and marginalization.
Audiovisual Access Policies and Procedures
Audiovisual materials have not been preserved and may not be available to researchers. Materials not yet digitized will need to have access copies made before they can be used. To request an access copy, or if you are unsure if an item has been digitized, please contact special.collections@nyu.edu with the collection name, collection number, and a description of the item(s) requested. A staff member will respond to you with further information.
Take Down Policy
Archived websites are made accessible for purposes of education and research. NYU Libraries have given attribution to rights holders when possible; however, due to the nature of archival collections, we are not always able to identify this information.
If you hold the rights to materials in our archived websites that are unattributed, please let us know so that we may maintain accurate information about these materials.
If you are a rights holder and are concerned that you have found material on this website for which you have not granted permission (or is not covered by a copyright exception under US copyright laws), you may request the removal of the material from our site by submitting a notice, with the elements described below, to the special.collections@nyu.edu.
Please include the following in your notice: Identification of the material that you believe to be infringing and information sufficient to permit us to locate the material; your contact information, such as an address, telephone number, and email address; a statement that you are the owner, or authorized to act on behalf of the owner, of an exclusive right that is allegedly infringed and that you have a good-faith belief that use of the material in the manner complained of is not authorized by the copyright owner, its agent, or the law; a statement that the information in the notification is accurate and made under penalty of perjury; and your physical or electronic signature. Upon receiving a notice that includes the details listed above, we will remove the allegedly infringing material from public view while we assess the issues identified in your notice.
Emigration and immigration law -- United States.; Web sites.; LGBTQ+ activism; LGBTQ+ communities; LGBTQ+ discrimination; Health care for LGBTQ+ people; LGBTQ+ people in ethnic groups; LGBTQ+ health education; LGBTQ+ immigration rights; LGBTQ+ people of color; Asian American LGBTQ+ people; Pacific Islander American LGBTQ+ people; Chin, Dennis; Tseng, Jason
- 15th Anniversary Banquet, 2005 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- 15th Anniversary Film, 2008; 1 DVD (Box 4)
- 1998 Beyond 2000 Sexual Health Survey, 1999 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- 1999 Winter Ball (Box 1, Folder 3)
- A Magazine, 2000 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- "American Identity" Program, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- amFAR AIDS Research Annual Report, 1998-1999 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Asian LGBT+ Movements Global Summit Programs, 2019 (Box 3, Folder 13)
- Asian Pride Project, 2014 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- The Audra Lorde Project, 2000 May 4 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- B2K, 1998-1999 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Banner, circa 1994-2014; 1 box In one oversize flat box (Box 9)
- Brix, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Brochures and Flyers, circa 1998-2014 (Box 1, Folder 11-12)
- Brooklyn Pride, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Business Cards, undated (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Business Cards, circa 1990s-2000s (Box 3, Folder 12)
- Bylaws, 1994 November (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Certificate of Recognition (City of New York), 2018 (Box 3, Folder 14)
- "Coming Out, Coming Home" Campaign, undated (Box 1, Folder 16)
- "Community Voices: The Next Gender Asian" Program, 2013 (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Dari Project, 2013 (Box 1, Folder 18)
- DC Connections, 1999 (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Details Magazine "Gay or Asian?" Response, 2004 April (Box 1, Folder 20)
- DowneTime Postcards, circa 2007-2013 (Box 1, Folder 21)
- Dragun, 1999 (Box 1, Folder 22)
- DynasTea Dance and Fundraiser, 1999-2006 (Box 1, Folder 23-25)
- Financial Summaries, 1998-1999 (Box 1, Folder 26)
- GAPIMNY News, 1999-2000 (Box 1, Folder 27-29)
- GAPIMNY Newsletter, 1995-1999 (Box 1, Folder 30)
- GAPIMNY Newsletter Page Proofs, 1999-2000 (Box 5, Folder 1)
- GAPIMNY Retreat, 1999 (Box 1, Folder 31)
- Gay City News, 2000 May 9 (Box 1, Folder 32)
- General Information Flyer About GAPIMNY, 2014 (Box 1, Folder 33)
- General Information Pamphlets About GAPIMNY, undated (Box 1, Folder 34)
- Green Tea Dance Party, 2000-2001 (Box 1, Folder 35)
- History of GAPIMNY, 2018 (Box 3, Folder 15)
- "Hong Kong Ex-Gay" Campaign Leaflets, undated (Box 1, Folder 36)
- "Honoring Our Heroes": Asian Pacific American Heritage Festival, 2001 May 6 (Box 1, Folder 37)
- HX, 1998-2006 (Box 1, Folder 38-40)
- "(In)Visibly American" Campaign, 2009 (Box 1, Folder 41)
- Lavendar Godzilla (Gay Asian Pacific Alliance), 2001 (Box 1, Folder 42)
- Lesbian and Gay New York, 2000-2002 (Box 1, Folder 43-44)
- "Love Goes with Any Gender" Campaign, circa 2000-2005 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- "Love Has No Borders" Campaign, circa 2000-2005 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Lunar New Year and Pride Parade: Banner, circa 1998-2014 (Box 6)
- Lunar New Year and Pride Parade: Horse Costume, 2014 (Box 8)
- Media Kits, 2000 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Membership and Support Flyers, 2013-2014 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Metrosource New York, 2000 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Mochi Balls, 2001 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Mug with GAPIMNY Logo, circa 1998-2014 (Box 7)
- National Queer Asian Pacific Islander Alliance (NQAPIA), 2009-2014 (Box 2, Folder 7-10)
- National Queer Asian Pacific Islander Alliance (NQAPIA): National Conference Video Highlights, 2009; 1 DVD (Box 4)
- New York Blade News, 2000-2002 (Box 2, Folder 11-13)
- Newspaper Clippings, 1996-2002 (Box 2, Folder 14)
- Next, 1998-2006 (Box 2, Folder 15-16)
- PersuAsian Newsmagazine, 2000-2007 (Box 2, Folder 17-23)
- Photograph Albums, circa 1998-2014 (Box 4)
- Planning Notes, 2013 (Box 5, Folder 2)
- Postcards, circa 2013 (Box 2, Folder 24)
- POZ, 2000 July (Box 2, Folder 25)
- "Reflections" 10th Anniversary Banquet, 2000 (Box 2, Folder 26-27)
- Rice Conference Materials, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 28-29)
- Rice Paper (Gay Asian Community Health Empowerment Project [GACHEP]), 2000 (Box 2, Folder 30)
- "The Rising Voice of Asian America": Asian Pacific American Heritage Festival, 2000 May (Box 2, Folder 31)
- "Springderella" Banquet, 2002 (Box 2, Folder 32)
- Starfruit Zine, 2019 (Box 3, Folder 16)
- Steering Committee, 1996-2006 (Box 3, Folder 1-5, Box 2, Folder 33)
- Steering Committee, 2018-2020 (Box 3, Folder 17)
- Stickers, circa 2000-2014 (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Ten (Asian American Writers' Workshop), 1999 (Box 3, Folder 7)
- Time Out New York, 1998, 2000 (Box 3, Folder 8-9)
- "Tongzhi/Comrade: Out in Asia America": Installation at Museum of Chinese in America, 2000 (Box 3, Folder 10)
- Trivia Leaflet, circa 2012 (Box 3, Folder 11)
- Archived Websites, December 2019-ongoing; 3 websites in 3 archived websites.
  Accruals
  New site crawls are accrued semiannually.
  Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
  Due to technical or privacy issues, archived websites may not be exact copies of the original website at the time of the web crawl. Certain file types will not be captured dependent on how they are embedded in the site. Other parts of websites that the crawler has difficulty capturing includes Javascript, streaming content, database-driven content, and highly interactive content. Full-Text searches of archived websites are available at https://archive-it.org/organizations/567.
  Appraisal
  Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of gaysiandiaries.com and gapimny.org in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
  Scope and Contents
  The GAPIMNY website is made up news and press releases, event listings, their platform and values, steering committee members, and their programming, including a leadership development program, their biweekly happy hour (Elixer), meetings and workshops, and political engagement organizing around immigration, racism, homophobia, and transgender exclusion. Events and programming are mostly focused around topics such as trans allyship, coming-out, local politics, and raising the visibility of issues regarding queer and trans Asian and Pacific Islanders. Also captured is GAPIMNY's blog, the Gaysian Diaries, which exists to create an online space for queer and trans Asian and Pacific Islanders to share their experiences. The GAPIMNY Linktree contains links to forms related to getting involved in events and fundraising; legislative tracking on LGBTQIA+ issues; and a history of the organization.